Guide to the Beyond the Pale Records TAM.718
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Beyond the Pale Records
1995-2014
1967-2019
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Neimark, Marilyn Kleinberg
Kaplan, Esther
Beyond the Pale (Radio program)
TAM.718
17.25 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons, 20 cassette boxes, 8 CD boxes, 2 LP boxes, and 1 half manuscript box.
256 Gigabytes in 603 computer files.
394 audiocassettes
273 sound cassettes (dat)
83 sound tape reels
279 sound discs (minidisc)
1 websites in 1 archived website.
Beyond the Pale was a weekly radio program produced and hosted by Esther Kaplan and Marilyn Kleinberg Neimark on New York's WBAI Radio, part of the Pacifica Radio Network. The show ran from 1995 to 2014 and engaged in local, national, and international political debate and analysis, and explored the arts and cultural trends from a progressive, Jewish perspective. The Beyond the Pale Records contain audio recordings from the radio program, and include an archived version of their website (https://www.beyondthepale.org), audiocassettes, ¼-inch audio reels, DATs, MiniDiscs, and CD-Rs of air-checks, event documentation, and source material. Materials in the collection date from from 1967-2019 with the bulk of materials dating 1995-2014. The radio show featured interviews with, and speeches and readings by, public figures; recordings of events; and discussions about contemporary political, social, and cultural issues impacting Jewish communities in the United States and abroad.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Esther Kaplan and Marilyn Kleinberg Neimark in 2017. The accession number associated with this gift is 2017.033.
In 2019, https://www.beyondthepale.org/ was added to the web archive and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.144.
Arrangement
Materials are intellectually arranged chronologically by year. Materials are physically arranged by format, and then chronologically by year.
Historical Note
Beyond the Pale was a radio program produced and hosted by Esther Kaplan and Marilyn Kleinberg Neimark on New York's WBAI Radio, part of the Pacifica Radio Network. The show ran steadily from 1995 to 2014 and explored local, national, and international political debate and analysis from a Jewish perspective. Produced with the support of the New York City-based Jews for Racial and Economic Justice (JFREJ), Beyond the Pale included discussions on contemporary Jewish culture from a leftist perspective with writers, filmmakers, musicians, critics, and political organizers.
Scope and Contents
The Beyond the Pale Records contains an archived website, audiocassettes, ¼-inch audio reels, DATs, MiniDiscs, and CD-Rs of Beyond the Pale audio recordings, which include air-checks, recordings of live broadcasts, events, and audio used as source material. Materials in the collection date from from 1967 to 2019 with the bulk of materials dating 1995-2014. The recordings in this collection document the discussions and debates surrounding both major world events and events in the history of progressive Jewish activism for nearly 20 years. The episodes cover Jewish culture, politics, and social issues, and though the programs are generally based on progressive concerns, the opinions expressed on the program represent viewpoints from not only the political left, but the right as well. Many programs focus on issues surrounding the Middle East conflict, U.S.-Israel and U.S.-Palestinian relations, and the recordings document the development of these issues over nearly two decades. There are interviews with many significant artists, scholars, activists, and politicians, such as Grace Paley, Adrienne Rich, Dr. Ruchama Marton, Michel Warschawski, Rabbi Arthur Waskow, Dr. Tal Jarus-Hakak, and others. The program covered discussions on many contemporary subjects within the American Jewish community including domestic abuse, LGBTQ issues, Jewish identity, the prison-industrial complex, and Jews and the religious right. The radio program also explored a number of historical events and their impacts on the present, such as the history of Jewish involvement in radical politics and labor activism, the trial and execution of Ethel and Julius Rosenberg, Jewish life in Eastern Europe and the USSR, and the Ocean Hill-Brownsville battle over community control of public schools in the late 1960s. Frequent contributors to and co-hosts of the program include Henry Foner, Melanie Kaye/Kantrowitz, Nan Rubin, Alisa Solomon, Josh Nathan-Kazis, and Abe Velez. Besides the October 2019 capture of the Beyond the Pale website (https://www.beyondthepale.org), there are additional captures by the WayBack Machine between 2008 and 2018.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library and Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Appraisal
During processing in 2019, three optical discs were found to be unreadable and discarded.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Community radio; Jews -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Judaism -- United States -- History.; Audiotapes.; New York (State) -- Politics and government.; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government.; Politics and culture.; Arab-Israeli conflict.; Neimark, Marilyn Kleinberg; Kaplan, Esther; Pacifica Radio
- Abba Eban; Tom Segev B'nai Jeshurun [1967-002], 1967 June 6; 2007 June 6 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_718_ER_1)
- Heschel on War [1973-001] (Box 1, Item 718_0001)
- Studs Terkel Interview; 1963, 1973 Specials [1973-002] (Box 1, Item 718_0002)
- Studs Terkel with Meridel Le Sueur, Reel 1 [1982-002], 1982-03-30 (Box 24, Item 718_0997)
- Studs Terkel with Meridel Le Sueur, Reel 2 [1982-001], 1982-03-30 (Box 24, Item 718_0996)
- Kung Pao Kosher Comedy - Audio Clips [1994-003] (Box 1, Item 718_0003)
- W.H. Kunstler Acceptance Speech [1994-001], 1994-06-01 (Box 21, Item 718_0926)
- Richie Perez Breaking Bread [1994-002], 1994-06-01 (Box 21, Item 718_0927)
- Ruchama Marton Psychology [2015-001], circa 1995-2007 (Box 23, Item 718_0990)
- Adrienne Cooper "I'm Not Afraid" [2015-002], circa 1995-2008 (Box 23, Item 718_0991)
- Teach-In [1995-019], 1995-02-05 (Box 1, Item 718_0022)
- Tony Kushner Reading; Cong. Jerrold Nadler on New Congress; Ruchama Martin Interview [1995-001], 1995-03-01 (Box 1, Item 718_0004)
- Tony Kushner Reading; Cong. Jerrold Nadler on New Congress; Ruchama Martin Interview [1995-038], 1995-03-01 (Box 2, Item 718_0041)
- Women's History [1995-002], 1995-03-15 (Box 1, Item 718_0005)
- Aircheck [1995-027], 1995-03-15 (Box 1, Item 718_0030)
- Women's History [1995-039], 1995-03-15 (Box 2, Item 718_0042)
- Jews for Racial and Economic Justice (JFREJ) [1995-003], 1995-03-21 (Box 1, Item 718_0006)
- Jews for Racial and Economic Justice (JFREJ) [1995-004], 1995-03-21 (Box 1, Item 718_0007)
- The Struggle to Save the City University of New York Show (CUNY Budget Cuts) [1995-026], 1995-03-21 (Box 1, Item 718_0029)
- The Struggle to Save the City University of New York (CUNY Show) [1995-040], 1995-03-21 (Box 2, Item 718_0043)
- The Struggle to Save the City University of New York Show [1995-021], 1995-03-21 (Box 1, Item 718_0023)
- Progressive Jewish Radio Hour: Passover Show [1995-018], 1995-04-12 (Box 1, Item 718_0021)
- Ma'yan Women's Seder, Tape 1, 1995-04-12 (Box 1, Item 718_0026)
- Ma'yan Women's Seder, Tape 2 [1995-024], 1995-04-12 (Box 1, Item 718_0027)
- Passover Show [1995-025], 1995-04-12 (Box 1, Item 718_0028)
- Passover Show [1995-029], 1995-04-12 (Box 1, Item 718_0032)
- Passover Show [1995-031], 1995-04-12 (Box 1, Item 718_0034)
- Passover Show [1995-047], 1995-04-12 (Box 2, Item 718_0050)
- Yom Hashoah [1995-008], 1995-04-19 (Box 1, Item 718_0010)
- Ruth Rubin Young and Hym [1995-023], 1995-04-19 (Box 1, Item 718_0025)
- Ruth Rubin Songs [1995-023], 1995-04-19 (Box 21, Item 718_0928)
- Jews and the Christian Right [1995-009], 1995-04-26 (Box 1, Item 718_0012)
- Jews and the Radical Right [1995-007], 1995-05-07; cuid2619 (Box 1, Item 718_0011, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_718_ER_617)
  Scope and Contents
  Jews and the Radical Right (2) [A] Slide Show: Andy Stettner & Sandi DuBowski (Stettner - People for the American Way; DuBowski - Public Policy Institute of Planned Parenthood) Q&A [B] Manhattan Borough President Ruth Messinger; State Assemblywoman Deborah Glick
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Original Format: Audio Cassette, Duration: 90 min.
- Jews and the Radical Right [1995-041], 1995-05-07; cuid2620 (Box 2, Item 718_0044, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_718_ER_618)
  Jews and the Radical Right: Daniel Levitas (cont.)-Ctr for Democratic Renewal, Lawrence Cohler- Jewish Week,
- Jews and the Radical Right [1995-042], 1995-05-07 (Box 2, Item 718_0045)
- Yiddish Revival [1995-045], 1995-05-31 (Box 2, Item 718_0048)
- Israel and Status of the Peace Process [1995-046], 1995-06-07 (Box 2, Item 718_0049)
- Labor Issues [1995-012], 1995-06-28 (Box 1, Item 718_0015)
- Fascism in Europe [1995-020], 1995-07-05 (Box 1, Item 718_1007)
- Newt Gingrich at the 92nd Street Y [1995-013], 1995-07-12 (Box 1, Item 718_0016)
- Mizrahi Jews [1995-014], 1995-07-19 (Box 1, Item 718_0017)
- Jews and Sexuality [1995-043], 1995-09-06 (Box 2, Item 718_0046)
- Holocausts Panel at Brecht Forum [1995-016], 1995-09-09 (Box 1, Item 718_0019)
- Readings and Performances: Judith Sloan, Tony Kushner, and Grace Paley [1995-010], 1995-10-01 (Box 1, Item 718_0013)
- Board of Education and Chancellor Search [1995-037], 1995-10-08 (Box 2, Item 718_0040)
- Gay and Lesbian Jews [1995-011], 1995-10-11 (Box 1, Item 718_0014)
- Jewish Radical Education Program with Mordechai Levy and John Ranz [1995-005], 1995-10-15 (Box 1, Item 718_0008)
- Gertrude Stein: Buffie Johnson, Eileen Myles, Maria Damon, and Charles Bernstein [1995-033], 1995-10-15 (Box 2, Item 718_0036)
- Christian Coalition Conference; Million Man March [1995-017], 1995-10-22 (Box 1, Item 718_0020)
- Richard John Neuhaus and Ismar Schorsch Lecture: "One Nation Under God: The Role of Religion in the Public Square" [1995-028], 1995-10-26 (Box 1, Item 718_0031)
- Women and Yiddish Conference: Irena Klepfisz and Frieda Forman, Tape 1 [1995-006], 1995-10-28 (Box 1, Item 718_0009)
- Women and Yiddish Conference: Performances by Adrienne Cooper et al, Tape 2 [1995-022], 1995-10-29 (Box 1, Item 718_0024)
- A: Christian Coalition Conference; Million Man March / B: Israel Film Festival; Women and Yiddish Conference [1995-036], 1995-10-29 (Box 2, Item 718_0039)
- William Kristol and Leonard Fein on Socioeconomic Problems [1995-032], 1995-11-09 (Box 1, Item 718_0035)
- Domestic Violence in the Jewish Community [1995-034], 1995-11-11 (Box 2, Item 718_0037)
- Attica; W.H. Kunstler [1995-049], 1995-11-26 (Box 21, Item 718_0929)
- Michel Warschawski on Palestinians within Israel [1995-015], 1995-12-12 (Box 1, Item 718_0018)
- Jewish Radio of the 40's and 50's [1995-035], 1995-12-31 (Box 2, Item 718_0038)
- Teach-in Opening Plenary [1996-020] (Box 3, Item 718_0070)
- Teach-in 1 [1996-021] (Box 3, Item 718_0071)
- Teach-in 2 [1996-022] (Box 3, Item 718_0072)
- Teach-in 3 [1996-023] (Box 3, Item 718_0073)
- Teach-in 4 [1996-024] (Box 3, Item 718_0074)
- Teach-in 5 [1996-025] (Box 3, Item 718_0075)
- Teach-in 7 [1996-026] (Box 3, Item 718_0076)
- Teach-in 8 [1996-027] (Box 3, Item 718_0077)
- Teach-in 9 [1996-028] (Box 3, Item 718_0078)
- Closing [1996-029] (Box 3, Item 718_0079)
- In Gerangl: End Police Brutality, Closing [1996-036] (Box 3, Item 718_0086)
- Blood Libel [1996-040] (Box 3, Item 718_0088)
- Police Brutality [2015-013], circa 1996-2014 (Box 11, Item 718_0383)
- Slideshow Song [2015-011], circa 1996-2014 (Box 11, Item 718_0925)
- Downtown Jewish Music [1996-016], 1996-01-01 (Box 2, Item 718_0066)
- Naomi Chazan and Rita Hauser of Temple Israel, NYC; Silent No More! Movement for Civil Rights and Peace (Ratz/CRM/Meretz) Education Fund for Israeli Civil Rights and Peace [1996-035], 1996-01-25 (Box 3, Item 718_0085)
- Panel at Columbia about Racism and Anti-Semitism [1996-032], 1996-02-05 (Box 3, Item 718_0082)
- Avraham Neguise on Ethiopian Jews and Israel Blood Scandal [1996-001], 1996-02-11 (Box 2, Item 718_0051)
- A: Ethiopians in Israel / B: Ethiopian Jews and Blood Scandal [1996-011], 1996 February 11; 1996 February 18 (Box 2, Item 718_0061)
- A: Women's Day / B: State Budget [1996-010], 1996 March 8; 1996 March 24 (Box 2, Item 718_0060)
- A: Purim Show / B: Leslie Feinberg on Transgender Warriors; Melanie Kaye/Kantrowitz Reading from Poems [1996-008], 1996 March 10; 1996 September 1 (Box 2, Item 718_0058)
- Arthur Waskow Interview [1996-002], 1996-03-28 (Box 2, Item 718_0052)
- Passover Show [1996-003], 1996-03-31 (Box 2, Item 718_0053)
- Passover Show [1996-009], 1996-03-31 (Box 2, Item 718_0059)
- Passover Show [1996-017], 1996-03-31 (Box 2, Item 718_0067)
- Sander Gilman Jewish Museum Lecture [1996-034], 1996-04-07 (Box 3, Item 718_0084)
- Labor Show [1996-041], 1996-04-28 (Box 3, Item 718_0089)
- A: CUNY New Union Efforts and Retrenchment Plan / B: Arthur Waskow on New Books Down-to-Earth Judaism and Godwrestling - Round 2 [1996-006], 1996-06-09; 1996-07-07; cuid2621 (Box 2, Item 718_0056, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_718_ER_619)
  Arthur Waskow: Interview about Arthur Waskow's new books, Down-to-Earth Judaism and God Wrestling Round 2, CUNY New Union Effort and the Retrenchment Plan: Barbara Bowen, chapter chair with the New Caucus at Queens College; Richard Boris, executive vice-president of the Professional Staff Congress; Sherry Gorelick, author of City College and the Jewish Poor; LaDonne? Student welfare activist? CUNY New Union efforts & retrenchment plan,
  Original Format: Audio Cassette, Duration: 120 min.
- Multiculturalism and Jews Panel at National Women's Studies Association Conference [1996-031], 1996 June 12-16 (Box 3, Item 718_0081)
- A: Jews and Sports / B: Sex Work [1996-007], 1996 July 21; 1996 July 28 (Box 2, Item 718_0057)
- Women and Yiddish Conference: Irene Klepfisz and Frieda Forman [1995-006], 1996 August 4; 1996 August 11 (Box 2, Item 718_0055)
- A: The Living Theater / B: Yom Kippur Show [1996-030], 1996 August 18; 1996 September 22 (Box 3, Item 718_0080)
- Educating the Next Generation [1995-044], 1996-08-23 (Box 2, Item 718_0047)
- Jewish Rock and Roll [1996-019], 1996-08-25 (Box 2, Item 718_0069)
- Melanie Kaye/Kantrowitz [1996-033], 1996-09-01 (Box 3, Item 718_0083)
- Janet Coleman of Arts in the Evening Interview with Allen Ginsberg [1996-038], 1996-09-01 (Box 21, Item 718_0930)
- A: Interfaith Relationships / B: Jews and Multiculturalism [1996-004], 1996 September 8; 1996 November 11 (Box 2, Item 718_0054)
- A: Welfare / B: In Gerangl [1996-014], 1996 October 20; 1996 October 27 (Box 2, Item 718_0064)
- A: Judy Helfand on Documentary A Healthy Baby Girl / B: Marcia Falk Interview [1996-015], 1996 November 10; 1996 November 17 (Box 2, Item 718_0065)
- National Women's Studies Conference: Multiculturalism and Jews [1996-018], 1996-11-24 (Box 2, Item 718_0068)
- COJO Investigations and JTS Tenants' Struggle [1996-012], 1996-12-15 (Box 2, Item 718_0062)
- A: Scratch / B: "The Day Santa Fainted" by Jenny Romaine [1996-037], 1996 December 20 (Box 3, Item 718_0087)
- A: Scratch / B: Folksbiene Sapora Spazman [1996-042], 1996-12-20 (Box 3, Item 718_0090)
- A: Christmas and Jews / B: Folksbiene's Production of The Maiden of Ludmir; Court Jews Exhibition at the Jewish Museum [1996-013], 1996 December 22; 1996 December 29 (Box 2, Item 718_0063)
- Music from Folksbiene's The Maiden of Ludmir; Interview with Zypora Spaisman [1996-039], 1996-12-29 (Box 21, Item 718_0931)
- Grace Paley [2015-004], circa 1997-2007 (Box 23, Item 718_0993)
- Grace Paley Readings: "The Hearer," "Traveling" [2015-005], circa 1997-2007 (Box 23, Item 718_0994)
- A: Michel Warschawski and Simona Sharoni on Hebron; Isabel Ganz of Alhambra / B: Yale Strom on Carpati [1997-025], 1997 January 1; 1997 March 16 (Box 4, Item 718_0115)
- A: Jews and Environmentalism / B: James McBride and Jewish Film Festival [1997-028], 1997 January 12; 1997 January 19 (Box 4, Item 718_0118)
- Frédérique Pressman on Anti-Immigrant Politics in France [1997-049], 1997-02 (Box 4, Item 718_0138)
- Marathon: Arthur Waskow Talk [1997-002], 1997-02-02 (Box 3, Item 718_0091)
- Ben Nadel, Secretary of Jewish Bund [1997-048], 1997-02-05 (Box 4, Item 718_0137)
- Organized Jewish Community, Tape 2 [1997-050], 1997-02-05 (Box 4, Item 718_0139)
- Organized Jewish Community, Tape 1 [1997-051], 1997-02-05 (Box 4, Item 718_0140)
- A: Immigration Politics in France and the U.S. / B: Davka and Response [1997-003], 1997 March 2; 1997 March 31 (Box 3, Item 718_0092)
- Women and Orthodoxy [1997-011], 1997-03-09 (Box 3, Item 718_0100)
- Women and Orthodoxy, Gila Svirsky [1997-043], 1997-03-09 (Box 4, Item 718_0132)
- Davka and Response [1997-022], 1997-03-30 (Box 4, Item 718_0112)
- Davka and Response [1997-055], 1997-03-30 (Box 5, Item 718_0144)
- Racial Justice Day [1997-046], 1997-04-07 (Box 4, Item 718_0135)
- Daniel Singer on Swiss Gold Furor [1997-026], 1997-04-13 (Box 4, Item 718_0116)
- A: Klezmatics Show: Alicia Svigals and Jennifer Miller (of Circus Amok); Passover / B: Jackie Robinson [1997-027], 1997 April 20; 1997 April 27 (Box 4, Item 718_0117)
- Jackie Robinson Conference at LIU: Lester Rodney and Henry Foner, Tape 1 [1997-009], 1997-04-27 (Box 3, Item 718_0098)
- Jackie Robinson Conference at LIU: Lester Rodney and Henry Foner, Tape 2 [1997-010], 1997-04-27 (Box 3, Item 718_0099)
- Jackie Robinson: Race, Sports and the American Dream: Siegel, Dorinson, and Levine [1997-031], 1997-04-27 (Box 4, Item 718_0120)
- Justice with a Sense of Humor [1997-023], 1997-05-04 (Box 4, Item 718_0113)
- Justice with a Sense of Humor [1997-024], 1997-05-04 (Box 4, Item 718_0114)
- A: Bund Show 100th Anniversary / B: Lorin Sklamberg Music Show [1997-019], 1997 May 5; 1998 August 30 (Box 4, Item 718_0109)
- Adrienne Rich and Grace Paley [1997-044], 1997-05-07 (Box 4, Item 718_0133)
- Grace Paley Reading "Traveling," JFREJ Benefit [1997-004], 1997-05-07 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_718_ER_2)
- Gary Rubin [1997-045], 1997-05-09 (Box 4, Item 718_0134)
- A: Welfare Bill / B: Rent Regulation; Torture in Israel [1997-29], 1997 May 11; 1997 May 18 (Box 4, Item 718_0119)
- Brad Lander of Fifth Avenue Committee [1997-036], 1997-05-18 (Box 4, Item 718_0126)
- A: Allegra Pacheco and Yifat Susskind on Israel and Palestine / B: Marty Rosenbluth, Director of Jerusalem: An Occupation Set in Stone [1997-056], 1997 May 18; 1997 June 11 (Box 5, Item 718_0145)
- Sweatshop Forum at Rodeph Sholom with Rabbi Camille Angel, Gail Malmgreen, and Ying Ng [1997-021], 1997-05-25 (Box 4, Item 718_0111)
- Miranda Bergman with Penny Rosenwasser, 1997-06-11 (Box 4, Item 718_0136)
- A: Palestine NGO Conference / B: Gay Pride Show [1997-006], 1997 June 15; 1997 June 22 (Box 3, Item 718_0094)
- A: Jewish Underground WWII Jewish Press [1997-007], 1997-06-29 (Box 3, Item 718_0095)
- JFREJ Benefit: Adrienne Rich Introduction, 1997-07-06 (Box 4, Item 718_0108)
- A: Jews and Rock and Roll / B: Jewish World Music [1997-032], 1997 July 13; 1997 November 11 (Box 4, Item 718_0121)
- A: Oren Rudofsky on Documentary A World Apart and Jonathan Cohen Interview with Bruce Kayton / B: Joyce Antler on The Journey Home; Naomi Seidman on A Marriage Made in Heaven: The Hebrew Yiddish Language Wars [1997-033], 1997 July 20; 1997 July 27 (Box 4, Item 718_0122)
- Miranda Bergman with Penny Rosenwasser, 1997-07-21 (Box 4, Item 718_0131)
- A: Grace Paley Reading at JREFJ's May Benefit; Penny Rosenwasser Interview with Miranda Bergman / B: Margarita Lopez, City Council Candidate; Gabriel Kahn on Lopez Race Against Judy Rapfogel [1997-034], 1997 August 3; 1997 August 17 (Box 4, Item 718_0123)
- Joel Yager - The Mountains, Catskills 1 [1997-012], 1997-08-24 (Box 3, Item 718_0101)
- Catskills Variety, Catskills 2 [1997-013], 1997-08-24 (Box 3, Item 718_0102)
- Karen Yager - The Mountains, Catskills 3 [1997-014], 1997-08-24 (Box 3, Item 718_0103)
- Karen Yager - The Mountains, Catskills 4 [1997-053], 1997-08-24 (Box 5, Item 718_0142)
- Joel Yager - The Mountains, Catskills 5 [1997-15], 1997-08-24 (Box 3, Item 718_0104)
- A: Primary Races / B: Grace Paley [1997-035], 1997-09-07 (Box 4, Item 718_0124)
- A: Report on Israel/Palestine and Mordechai Vanunu with Imad Sabi / B: Bund Show [1997-038], 1997-09-14; 1997-10-05; cuid2623 (Box 4, Item 718_0127, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_718_ER_621)
  Report on Israel/Palestine and Mordechai Vanunu Co-host, Yifat Susskind, formerly of the Alternative Information Center in Jerusalem; with Imad Sabi, recently released Administrative Detainee currently studying in Holland; and Gideon Spiro of The Committee to Free Mordechai Vanunu, 100th Anniversary of the Bund Jack Jacobs, John Jay College-CUNY, Dr. Benjamin Nadel, Secretary of the Bund, and Aaron Taub, archivist, YIVO,
- Beginning Anew: Women and High Holidays [1997-020], 1997-09-28 (Box 4, Item 718_0110)
- The Jewish Labor Bund, 1997-10-05; cuid2622 (Box 4, Item 718_0107, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_718_ER_620)
  100th Anniversary of the Bund Jack Jacobs, John Jay College-CUNY, Dr. Benjamin Nadel, Secretary of the Bund, and Aaron Taub, archivist, YIVO
  Original Format: Audio Cassette, Duration: 60 min.
- The Bund Anniversary [1997-039], 1997-10-05 (Box 4, Item 718_0128)
- The Jewish Labor Bund [1997-040], 1997-10-05 (Box 4, Item 718_0129)
- The Jewish Labor Bund [1997-052], 1997-10-05 (Box 4, Item 718_0141)